liquor.com 2018-11-05

# Privacy Policy

Last updated May 25, 2018

This Privacy Policy describes how Liquor.com Holdings Inc. (“Liquor.com”) collects, uses and stores the information we get when you visit our website and/or register for our email newsletter. We collect your data (specifically outlined below), such as email address and other details, which are mostly related to your spirit preferences, content preferences and location in order to send you our email newsletters, invitations to events and other programs, including personalized marketing, advertising and content experiences. We will never share your information without your explicit permission. Please read this notice carefully.

If you do not agree with any part of this Privacy Policy, do not use any of Liquor.com’s website or services. If at any any time you wish to remove your data from our systems, we will comply. (See “How to Ask Us to Delete Your Data” below.)

## HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We use the personal information (such as email address) that you directly provide to us for the following purposes:

  * To send you our email newsletter
  * To provide you with access to relevant content and advertisement
  * To allow you to log into your personal Liquor.com account

In certain specific cases, we will be contractually obligated to share your data with a third-party advertiser or partner (for example, cocktail competitions, special events or sweepstakes). In these cases, we will make it clear that your data is being shared to the third party. You always have the option to not have your data shared by not taking part in the specific program.

Liquor.com will not share your personal information to any third party without your permission, except to select third parties who help run our website and send our emails. They will only use this information to serve our needs and are prohibited from using it in any other instance. The third parties we use for EU users are Google (website analytics/tracking and optimization), Quantcast (website analytics/tracking), ComScore (website analytics/tracking), SpotIM (comments), SailThru (email), JWPlayer (video player), GetSocial (social sharing and tracking), Facebook (for personalized accounts), AddThis (social sharing and tracking) and Tidal (blog account management). Please email us at [support@liquor.com](mailto:support@liquor.com) for an up-to-date list of third parties we use for users outside of the EU.

We use non-personally identifiable information (such as links you click on) for the following purposes:

  * To analyze profile or behavioral data to help us improve the content and products we offer you
  * To improve our site
  * To track usage trends to prepare for traffic load demands
  * To efficiently distribute our emails
  * To offer you invitations to events and other programs you may be interested in
  * To serve personalized ad experiences
  * To diagnose problems with our server so you can have an error-free experience

In specific cases, we may aggregate parts of this data and share this information in an anonymous form with our third-party advertisers or partners. This data will not contain any personally identifiable information about you or any other person.

## THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

On our website and in our emails, you will be presented with the opportunity to sign up for newsletters, submit your information to access content and special features, enter contests and sweepstakes, and more.

The type of information collected on those pages generally includes but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * Name
  * Mailing/billing address
  * Spirits preference
  * Job title
  * Location
  * Company name
  * Company address
  * Annual income
  * Buying preference
  * Age / date of birth
  * Gender

We collect information about you automatically when you visit our website or interact with our emails. The type of information collected generally includes but is not limited to:

  * Content you visited
  * Time spent on page
  * Number of pages visited
  * How often you visit our site
  * Links clicked
  * Determining if you found our content from another website
  * Your internet protocol (IP) address—it’s usually associated with the place from which you enter the internet, like your internet service provider, your company or your university.

Based on the information you provide to us, we may create or add other information to your profile in the interest of better serving you (for example, providing you with personalized recipe recommendations).

**We also use cookies.** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a website’s computers and is stored on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to allow us to quickly check your status as a subscriber and facilitate access to your preferences. If you don’t want cookies, your web browser likely includes an option that allows you to not accept them. More information about disabling/deleting cookies can be found here: [allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/stop-cookies-installed.html](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/stop-cookies-installed.html)

Please note that without cookies you may not be able to fully use all of our features. You can find out more about cookies and how they work here: [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## HOW WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION

All information described above is stored on nonpublic database servers.

## HOW LONG WE STORE YOUR INFORMATION

We will store your information indefinitely unless you follow the instructions to delete your data as described below.

## HOW TO REQUEST THE INFORMATION WE STORE ABOUT YOU

If you would like to request the information we store about you, please email us at [support@liquor.com](mailto:support@liquor.com) with the subject “My Stored Data.”

## HOW TO ASK US TO DELETE YOUR DATA

If you would like to unsubscribe from our communications at any time, you may do so in the footer of any of our emails. If you would like us to delete your information entirely, please fill out [this form](http://bit.ly/2tCaCKo). Otherwise, by continuing to interact with our website and emails, you provide us with permission to manage and use your data as described above.

## HOW TO UNSUBSCRIBE FROM EMAILS

You can opt out of receiving email communications at any time by clicking the “Manage Subscription” link found in the footer of all of our emails.

## THE DATA AND COOKIES THAT THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISERS AND PARTNERS COLLECT

Some of the ads appearing on Liquor.com are delivered to you by our web advertising partners. Information about your visit to their site, such as the number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address or other personal information), is used to serve ads to you.

Some of our advertisers may serve you cookies as well. If you don’t want cookies, your web browser likely includes an option that allows you to not accept them. More information about disabling/deleting cookies can be found here: [allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/stop-cookies-installed.html](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/stop-cookies-installed.html)

Please note that without cookies you may not be able to cancel opt-outs that rely on cookies, such as targeted advertising opt-outs. You can find out more about cookies and how they work here: [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

## HOW TO TURN OFF PERSONALIZED (TARGETED) ADVERTISING

To opt out of personalized content and advertising, you can do so through the Network Advertising Initiative ([optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)) and Digital Advertising Alliance ([optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/)) Some of the third-party advertising companies run on the website may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies ([networkadvertising.org](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/)).

You may opt out of mobile ad targeting by following the instructions posted [here](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074) (for iOS) and [here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en) (for Android).

## PARENTAL DISCRETION

Liquor.com is intended for use by adults of legal drinking age. Legal drinking age is defined as the age at which one is legally allowed to buy and drink alcohol in their location of residence. For example, in the United States of America, the legal drinking age is 21 years old and above. Liquor.com is not intended for use by children, especially those under age 13, or anyone under legal drinking age. No one under age 13 is allowed to use the site, provide any personal information or receive our email distributions. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17 must get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before viewing the website. If we learn that a user is below legal drinking age, we will promptly delete any accounts and all personal information that has been provided to us.

## LINKS TO OTHER SITES

Liquor.com may create links allowing you to access third-party sites. Liquor.com is not responsible for the content that appears on those sites and does not endorse these sites. Please read those sites’ individual privacy policies to see how they’ll use your data.

## MODIFICATION TO THIS POLICY

Liquor.com reserves the right to change this policy from time to time. However, all changes will be posted to this Privacy Policy at the time such changes are made. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page, so please check back.

Please note that continued access of Liquor.com will constitute your acceptance of any changes or revisions to the Privacy Policy.

Thank you for taking the time and interest to review our policies at Liquor.com. If you have concerns or questions about any aspect of the Liquor.com Privacy Policy, please contact us. We welcome your questions and feedback.

Please send all emails to: [support@liquor.com](mailto:support@liquor.com).

Thank you,

Liquor.com
